Good morning. Today we would like to introduce our Stem product to you within
goal free. We've chosen Goal 3.9.
We want to prevent people from dying from accidental carbon
monoxide poisoning. But why can't people stay away from
these gases? Because these chemicals are odorless and
is hard to identify with only smell. And most people
can't afford a well developed system to detect gases in households.
We would like to develop a system that keep on monitoring the presence
of a certain gases and give warning to people. If a certain gas is
detected, the device will send warnings to people around it and the users
can check the exact concentration of the gas in the air through
a system. This is our prototype using an Arduino
board. On the front there is a two four
a LCD screen. It can be used to
show the data of the sensors and help the user to check if it
is allowed to communicate using different methods.
We will introduce this later. By looking at
the site we can see that there's the Adjournal uno board
as the processing center of the system and
Evernet Shield for Adrenal uno to get access to the Internet.
And by looking at the back you can see the two sensors
and the potential meter for testing.
There are three outputs for the system using Arduino board.
Firstly, it can show the data directly on the LCD display
as shown. Secondly, it can transfer the data to
the app on your smartphone using Bluetooth, but the process
is a bit slow as an alternative.
The alternative can also send the data to an IP address
as a web page. If you want to know more about how the system works,
you may refer to this document. If you want to understand how
the gas sensors detect the gases, you may visit this website for the
details. Thank you.